<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Adrian Muscat</title>
    <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Adrian Muscat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🧑‍🏫 Presentations</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not much here but I hope to do more in the future, maybe even YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;PowerShell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work I decided to share my knowledge of PowerShell with collegues. This also helped me understand concepts better as I had to dig deeper and really understand what I was talking about. It was fun to do and I also got to improve my presentation and public speaking skills and at the same time offer help and advice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Tools &amp; Scripts</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/pstools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/pstools/</guid>
      <description>A collection of PowerShell tools and scripts I have developed for various tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab: Proxmox &amp; Ansible Automation</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:18:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/homelab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I run a homelab environment to experiment with virtualization, automation, and IT infrastructure. My main hypervisor is &lt;strong&gt;Proxmox VE&lt;/strong&gt;, which allows me to manage virtual machines and containers efficiently. I have been trying to improve my skills with Ansible and wanted to apply what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my homelab. This is also a good way to document things that I normally do when I create VMs like installing the QEMU agent and creating new users on them and it helps me to automate the process of creating new VMs and containers when I need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🛠️ Automating Sophos Uninstall Across Hundreds of PCs—Without Disrupting Users</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/endpoint-uninstall-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:18:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/endpoint-uninstall-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Migrating from Sophos to Defender for Endpoint came with a major challenge: tamper protection. To tackle it, I built a PowerShell module that interacts with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.sophos.com/docs/endpoint-v1/1/overview&#34;&gt;Sophos Central API&lt;/a&gt; to disable tamper protection remotely. You can check it out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adrimus/pssophoscentral&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup saved countless hours, avoided manual intervention, and kept users blissfully unaware—just the way it should be. If you’re facing a similar migration, feel free to explore or fork the modules, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to finish the module and did not include all the necessary components like paging as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with more than 200 endpoints. Always happy to connect with others tackling endpoint automation!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
