<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Adrian Muscat</title>
    <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adrian Muscat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 18:09:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://adrianmuscat.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/posts/growthmindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 18:09:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/posts/growthmindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently completed a course for assistant managers and learned about something called a “growth mindset.” Turns out, I’ve had one all along—I just didn’t know it had a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-that-stuck&#34;&gt;Lessons That Stuck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges = growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback isn’t personal—it’s fuel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills improve with effort and repetition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure is the path to success not the opposite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-influences&#34;&gt;External Influences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was about 11 years old I made many mistakes playing football in the street with my friends. I was not very good at it, but I loved the game. One of my best friends said that I was really bad at it. That didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from playing, but it was comments like that which could have discouraged me and unconsciously made me have a fixed mindset when I encountered difficulty at something. Instead, I kept playing and practicing, and eventually I got better. This experience taught me that external influences can shape our mindset, but we have the power to choose how we respond to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab: Proxmox &amp; Ansible Automation</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:18:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/homelab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I run a homelab environment to experiment with virtualization, automation, and IT infrastructure. My main hypervisor is &lt;strong&gt;Proxmox VE&lt;/strong&gt;, which allows me to manage virtual machines and containers efficiently. I have been trying to improve my skills with Ansible and wanted to apply what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my homelab. This is also a good way to document things that I normally do when I create VMs like installing the QEMU agent and creating new users on them and it helps me to automate the process of creating new VMs and containers when I need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🛠️ Automating Sophos Uninstall Across Hundreds of PCs—Without Disrupting Users</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/endpoint-uninstall-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:18:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/projects/endpoint-uninstall-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Migrating from Sophos to Defender for Endpoint came with a major challenge: tamper protection. To tackle it, I built a PowerShell module that interacts with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.sophos.com/docs/endpoint-v1/1/overview&#34;&gt;Sophos Central API&lt;/a&gt; to disable tamper protection remotely. You can check it out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adrimus/pssophoscentral&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup saved countless hours, avoided manual intervention, and kept users blissfully unaware—just the way it should be. If you’re facing a similar migration, feel free to explore or fork the modules, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to finish the module and did not include all the necessary components like paging as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with more than 200 endpoints. Always happy to connect with others tackling endpoint automation!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🔐 Assigning API Permissions to Managed Identities in Azure</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/posts/apipermissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/posts/apipermissions/</guid>
      <description>A step-by-step PowerShell guide for assigning Microsoft Graph permissions to Azure managed identities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Resources</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/posts/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/posts/resources/</guid>
      <description>A curated list of resources and books to help you in your tech career</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://adrianmuscat.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adrianmuscat.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Learn more about who I am and what I do</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
